wowair.us 2019-04-04

# WOW air's Privacy Policy | WOW air

Booking a flight ticket? Checking in for your next flight online? That means you are entrusting us with your personal data.   

Your personal privacy is very important to us and this page outlines our policy concerning personal information. By using our website, wowair.com, services or otherwise interacting with WOW air, you are accepting the practices and policies described in this Privacy Policy.

We really, really, want you to know the following items:

  1. Who are we and why do we have a Privacy Policy?  

  2. What do we mean by personal data and data processing?  

  3. What personal data do we collect?  

  4. How do we collect personal data?  

  5. How and why do we use personal data?  

  6. Cookies or other tracking technologies  

  7. Do we share personal data? And if so, why?  

  8. What is our legal basis for using your personal information?  

  9. Your rights - Requesting access to your personal data  

  10. Security of your personal data  

  11. Transfer of personal data to other countries  

  12. Updates to our Privacy Policy  

  13. Who can I talk to about this Privacy Policy?

## 1\. Who are we and why do we have a Privacy Policy?

Any references in this Privacy Policy to “WOW air”, “we”, “us” or “our” means WOW air ehf., a company registered in Iceland with registration number no. 451011-0220 and registered office at Katrinartuni 12, 105 Reykjavik, Iceland. WOW air is the “data controller” for the purposes of the Icelandic Data Protection Act and other applicable European data protection legislation. This means WOW air controls the ways your personal data is collected and is responsible for defining the purposes for processing your personal data.

We do collect personal data relating to you. However, we are committed to ensuring your right to privacy and will only process your personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies to the personal data WOW air collects and uses.

Below, we will explain how we collect, use, transfer, store or otherwise process any personal data relating to you. Our aim is to be as clear, transparent and candid as possible. Should you still have questions about how we process your personal data, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@wow.is](mailto:dpo@wow.is).

Without prejudice to your rights under applicable laws, this Privacy Policy is not contractual and does not form part of your contract with us.

 _To sum up…  _

 _This Privacy Policy provides important information about how WOW air collects and treats your information.   Please read it carefully._

## 2\. What do we mean by personal data and data processing?

When we use the term “personal data” in this Privacy Policy, we mean any information relating to you and through which you can be identified, directly or indirectly, or in combination with other information that we may hold. Personal data may include all sorts of things, for example, your name, phone number, email address, payment details, information relating to your travel itinerary (e.g. your booking reference number) or information on how you use our website and app or how you otherwise interact with us.

When we use the term “processing” of personal data, we mean any operation or set of operations performed on personal data, whether or not by automated means. All actions carried out on personal data, from collection and storage to alteration, use or disclosure thus constitute ‘processing’, e.g. we process your personal data when you change your booking or otherwise seek other support from us or when we send you newsletters or offers based on your preferences. 

 _To sum up…_

 _Personal data is data you can be identified from and data processing is us using the data in one way or another.   _

## 3\. What personal data do we collect?

The types of personal data that we collect will depend on our relationship with you, the circumstances of collection and the type of service you request from us. The personal data we collect and process may include: 

Your name, e-mail address, phone number, postal address and contact details. Additional information may be requested, such as information concerning your passport, date of birth, your gender, the number and type of your travel document (passport), its expiry date and country of issue.

Details collected regarding your bookings and your travel itinerary, such as date, origin, and destination for the trip, type of tickets and services bought, seat purchase, any luggage purchase, pre-ordered meals, duration of stay, time of purchase and amounts paid. Also, information about the purchase of products available on board.

Any information related to changes to your bookings or any travel products that relate to your bookings, for example if you purchase travel insurance, buy a tour, rent a car or book a hotel along with your flight booking.

Information concerning your dietary requirements or health, for example if you have a medical condition that may affect your flight, or if you need wheelchair services (see further below regarding sensitive personal data for more information).

Payment or transaction details (for example credit/debit card number and expiration date) regarding the purchase of products or services. 

Any information concerning customer care and travel irregularities, such as delayed or canceled flights, lost or delayed luggage, and complaints, refunds, and compensation.

Any communications or feedback you exchange with us, such as your emails, letters, calls, or your messages or posts on social media directed to us. 

Details about how you use WOW air’s website or our mobile app, such as your searches for flights.

We realize that special categories of data, such as data revealing race, ethnicity, religion or health, are particularly sensitive. We will only collect and use such sensitive data in accordance with this Privacy Policy where you have given your explicit consent, it is necessary, or you have deliberately made it public. For example, we do need to know if you are in your third trimester of pregnancy or require a wheelchair to board a flight, which reveals information about your health. Also, if you inform us about certain dietary requirements you have, this could indicate that you have specific religious beliefs. If you do not allow us to process any sensitive personal data, WOW air may be unable to provide all or parts of the services you have requested from us. 

 _To sum up…_

 _We collect and store certain personal data about you, mainly based on information you provide us with regarding yourself or the service you otherwise request from us.  _

## 4\. How do we collect personal data?

We collect your personal data whenever you use our services (both services provided directly by us or by other companies or agents we work with), our website, call center or mobile applications, when you travel with us. This includes, for example:

  * when you book, search or browse for a flight or other products or services on our website or mobile apps;  

  * when you register to receive our newsletters or other communications;  

  * when you join our MyWOW club, enter into one of our competitions, register for a promotion, complete one of our surveys or otherwise interact with us;  

  * when you complete a customer survey or provide us with feedback;  

  * when you interact with us via social media services, such as Facebook or Twitter.  

We may also receive your personal data from suppliers who provide services to you on our behalf. This includes, for example, our partners when you purchase their travel-related products or third parties like travel agents or other parties who book a flight for you. You should know that if you book a flight on behalf of someone else, you must have their consent to use their personal information.

 _To sum up…_

 _Your personal data may be provided directly by you, or WOW air may collect the data based on your use of our website, app or services._

## 5\. How and why do we use personal data?

We collect and process personal data for the following purposes:

### A) To provide our services to you and to manage your travel bookings

When you book a flight with us, we use your data to perform our services in relation to your flight and to deliver other services you have asked us to provide, for example to process and manage your booking, to verify credit or other charge card details, issue your flight ticket, check you in for your flight, accept you on board and get you to your destination. We also use your information when you are using our airport services, such as when you check in at our desks at the airport. 

 _To sum up…_

 _We use your personal data to get you from A to B._

### B) To communicate with you and manage our relationship with you

We may need to use your contact information to keep you informed of your bookings. We will send you confirmation of your bookings and your payment. We may also send you reminders or information regarding your flight, for example when the check-in opens, gate change information and to advise you of any disruption and changes to your flight. If you are using our mobile app, we may also send you app notifications for these purposes. These communications are made for operational purposes, not for marketing purposes, and as such, you will continue to receive them even if you opt-out from receiving marketing communications.

If you contact customer support, send us a request, fill in a web-form through our website or contact us on social media, we will process your personal data to identify you and help you as best we can, for example in relation to mishandled or missing baggage claims or responding to other inquiries or requests. We may also examine the content of our communication with you, for example, the correspondence between us where we deal with your complaint, to improve our services and experiences for customers. 

 _To sum up…_

 _We use your personal data to give you information about your flight, to respond to your inquiries and to improve our services._

### C) To personalize and improve your customer experience

We strive to improve and simplify your booking experience while also tailoring our services to your needs and preferences. We want to give you a personalized customer experience. In order to do all these things, we may use your personal data. For example, by knowing your preferred departure airport – we can provide you with offers for flights relevant to your location, as well as enabling us to provide you with more relevant communications on our webpage and in other channels. 

We may also collect information on which products or services you buy, how you use our website, etc. We do this in an effort to better understand what you like. We may use this information to personally tailor the content and offers you see, for example by delivering messages, offers and information that we think is relevant and may be of interest to you, prior to, during, and after your travel with us. They may also be used to personalize the services, content and offers on our websites and other sales and service channels including third-party websites and applications and via social media services.

 _To sum up…_

 _We use your personal data to personalize our services and improve the customer experience to your liking._

### D) For marketing

We may want to send you marketing communications for our flights, services, competitions, promotions or events. In addition, we may send you offers related to your upcoming flights or communications promoting our partner’s products and services that may relate to your travel arrangements. For this purpose, we may process your personal data, such as e-mail address, booking history or campaign participation history. 

 _To sum up…_

 _We use your personal data to personalize the marketing communications you receive from us to your liking._

### E) To improve ourselves and to protect our business interests

We may use personal data to conduct statistical and marketing analyses for our products and services or products and services of third parties. Furthermore, we may use the personal data to research or improve our products, services and marketing activities. 

We also use personal data to protect our business interests. For example, we will be using data related to you, for example your name, email address, IP address and other credit card information for fraud screening, safety, security and legal purposes.

 _To sum up…_

 _We use your personal data to improve our services and for marketing analysis. We also use it to make sure your payment is valid and non-fraudulent._

### F) To fulfil our legal obligations

We may process your personal data to comply with our legal obligations, for instance when we are obliged to maintain or provide information to government authorities or border control agencies. For this purpose, the data we process may include your name, address, e-mail address, IP address, payment details and passport details.

 _To sum up…_

 _Sometimes, we are under a legal obligation to process your personal data.  _

## 6\. Cookies or other tracking technologies

We use cookies or other technologies to improve our services, to provide you with more relevant content and to analyze how visitors use our website and app. Cookies allow us to recognize your device or computer and to see how you interact with our website. 

For example, cookies give you features such as remembering aspects of your last flight search to make the next search faster. You can modify your browser settings to decline cookies, but this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website or our app. For more information, see our [Cookie Policy](https://wowair.com/cookie-policy/).

 _To sum up…_

 _We use cookies. If you want more information, read through our Cookie Policy._

## 7\. Do we share personal data? And if so, why?

We may share some of your personal data, or obtain your personal data, to/from certain third parties as follows:

  * Airports, law enforcement and government authorities when required by law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request. For example, there are specific destinations where we are required to provide your personal data to border control agencies with information that relates to your documents and travel itinerary (Advance Passenger Information).  

  * Travel agents or other such companies through which you book your services with us or otherwise interact with us on your behalf, including when you make an inquiry with a travel agent but do not proceed to a booking.  

  * Payment service providers such as credit and debit card companies. You will be providing us with your payment details in addition to other personal data to complete your payment. These data, for instance, your name, address, e-mail address and IP address will be disclosed to our payment service provider to complete your booking. In order to prevent and detect fraudulent transactions, we may also share your data with a fraud screening partner.   

  * Third party service providers who perform operations or work on our behalf and on our instructions as data processors. These service providers help us to run our business and improve our services as well as your customer experience. For instance, we will need to share your data with our ground handling agents who handle your check in at the airport you are traveling from. We may also share your data with our call center or other companies who help us get your feedback on our services.   

  * Business partners who offer related products or services which we think may interest you. We do allow third parties to make offers available through our website. If you decide to purchase their services or products, some of your personal data may be disclosed to that third party.   

  * Other business partners. We may share aggregated data for the purposes of improving our service, research, statistics and system administration.   

  * Also note that through our website we sometime provide links to third party websites which are subject to separate Privacy Policies. Please be aware that this Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites and that we are not responsible for your information that third parties may collect through these websites.  

 _To sum up…_

 _We will share personal data with third parties to best provide WOW air’s services, or where we are legally obliged to, and in special situations such as legal investigations. We may also share data with third parties that help us prevent fraud and analyze website activity._

## 8\. What is our legal basis for using your personal information?

We will only process your personal data where we have a legal basis to do so. The legal basis will depend on the reason we collected and our need to use your information. Our legal basis for the processing of your personal data are:  

  * We need to use your data so that we can provide our services to you, that is to, process your booking, fulfil your travel arrangements and otherwise perform the contract we have with you.  

  * It is in our legitimate interest as an airline to use your data in order to operate and improve our business as an airline or a travel provider.  

  * We need to use your data in order to comply with legal obligations.  

  * We need to use your data to protect the vital interest of you are another person.  

  * You have given us consent to use your information in a particular manner.  

As further explained below, where the basis of our processing is consent, you can withdraw your consent to such processing at any time. 

 _To sum up…_

 _We only process personal data if we have a legal basis to do so._

## 9\. Your rights - Requesting access to your personal data

You do have certain rights in relation to your personal data. Your rights include the following:

  1. Right to know whether we hold information about you and, if so, what that information is and further details how/why we use and process your personal information.  

  2. Right of access to your personal information we hold. If requested (see below) you will receive an electronic copy of the personal information we hold about you.   

  3. Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you, for example if it is inaccurate.  

  4. Request erasure of your personal data (or to be “forgotten”). In certain instances, you can ask us to delete or remove personal data, for example where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below).  

  5. Right to revoke consent to the processing of data where consent is relied upon by us as the basis of processing for a specific purpose. You have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time. If we receive notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will no longer process your information for the purpose or purposes you originally agreed to, unless we have a legal basis to do so or if your withdrawal of consent was limited to certain processing activities. Please note that if you withdraw this consent it may mean we will not be able to provide all or parts of the services you have requested from us.  

  6. Object to processing of your personal data if we are relying on a legitimate interest as a basis for our processing unless our reasons for the underlying processing outweighs your interests, rights and freedoms. Also, you have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes. Please note if you exercise this right in relation to WOW air‘s marketing communications we will no longer send you marketing communications. However, we will still send you communications about the services you have booked to use, such as your travel itinerary.  

  7. Object to automated decision-making, such as profiling, that is not to be subject of any automated decision-making by us using your personal information or profiling of you. We do point out that although we use personal information to personalize our services and offers to you we don't engage in automated processing.  

  8. Request transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party (also known as data portability). This enables you to take your data from us in an electronically useable format and to be able to transfer your data to another party in an electronically useable format.  

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please visit our [data request page](https://wowair.com/privacy/requesting-your-personal-data-wow-air/) or contact us, see section “Who can I talk to about this Privacy Policy?” below.

 _To sum up…_

 _You have many rights concerning your data and if you want to exercise them please let us know.  _

## 10\. Security of your personal data

We take the appropriate security measures to safeguard the collection, transmission and storage of the data we collect in order to prevent it from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. We use encryption where required. This includes the use of SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology, which is the industry standard method of encrypting personal information and payment information so that they can be transferred via the internet in a safe manner. SSL makes sure that information is encrypted as it travels from your computer or mobile device to WOW air’s booking engine.

If your browser does not support SSL, we recommend that you upgrade to the latest version of any browser to enhance the security of further transactions, otherwise the transmission of your personal data may not be protected and WOW air disclaims any responsibility in this regard.

In addition, we limit access to your personal data within WOW air and our service providers to a “business need to know”. In other words: they are not to be able to access or process your data unless they need to, and where they need to, they are doing it on our instructions, under a duty of confidentiality and have appropriate technical and operational security measures in place to protect your data.

Furthermore, we have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. 

 _To sum up…_

 _We do our absolute best to keep your data safe._

## 11\. Transfer of personal data to other countries

WOW air operates in multiple jurisdictions, some of which are not located in European Union (“EU”) or the European Economic Area (“EEA”), such as Israel, Canada and USA. As such, we will be transferring personal data to countries outside of the EEA which do not always have strong data protection laws. Transfer of personal data to a third country outside of the EEA will only take place if appropriate safeguards under EU law which legitimise data transfers outside are provided, such as by entering into standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission. The standard contractual clauses can be found on the European Commission website.

 _To sum up…_

 _We will transfer data to countries outside the EEA – but only in accordance with EU law._

## 12\. Updates to our Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may make changes to this Privacy Policy. Changes will be   communicated to you by way of an e-mail or a notice on our website.

 _To sum up…_

 _If we change this policy – we’ll let you know._

## 13\. Who can I talk to about this Privacy Policy?

Please do not hesitate to contact us if you have any questions or comments about this Privacy policy. You can reach us online at [dpo@wow.is](mailto:dpo@wow.is). You may also write to us at: 

WOW air’s Data Protection Officer  
WOW air HQ  
Katrinartun 12  
105 Reykjavik  
ICELAND

If you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to complain to the relevant data protection authorities, which in our case is the Icelandic Data Protection Authority (see [www.personuvernd.is](https://www.personuvernd.is/)).

 _To sum up…_

 _If you have any questions regarding this Policy, let us know._
